<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>info.portfolio_performance.PortfolioPerformance</id>
  <name>Portfolio Performance</name>
  <summary>Track the performance of an investment portfolio</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Analysiere die Performance Deines gesamten Anlageportfolios</summary>
  <url type="homepage">https://www.portfolio-performance.info/en/</url>
  <icon type="remote">https://www.portfolio-performance.info/images/logo.svg</icon>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>EPL-1.0</project_license>
  <description>
    <p>An open source tool to calculate the overall performance of an investment portfolio - across all accounts - using True-Time Weighted Return or Internal Rate of Return.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Record the full history of your transactions: purchases, sales, taxes, fees, ...</li>
      <li>Calculate performance indicators such as the True-Time Weighted Rate of Return or the Internal Rate of Return (IRR) for your holdings.</li>
      <li>Update historical quotes from a variety of sources: Yahoo Finance, Finnhub.io, Quandl, or AlphaVantage. Alternatively, scrape quotes from HTML pages or JSON documents.</li>
      <li>All data is stored in XML for further processing and can be exported as CSV or JSON.</li>
      <li>Rebalance your investment portfolio based on a freely defined Asset Allocation.</li>
      <li>Keep foreign currency accounts using the exchange rates published by the European Central Bank (ECB).</li>
    </ul>
    <p xml:lang="de">Ein Open Source Programm zur Berechnung der Performance eines Gesamtportfolios - über verschiedene Depots und Konten hinweg - anhand von True-Time Weighted Rate of Return und internem Zinsfuß.</p>
    <ul xml:lang="de">
      <li>Die vollständige Historie aller Buchungen kann erfasst werden: Käufe, Verkäufe, Steuern, Gebühren, ...</li>
      <li>Performance-Kennzahlen wie der True-Time Weighted Rate of Return oder der interne Zinsfuß (Internal Rate of Return) werden errechnet.</li>
      <li>Historische Kurse werden automatisch von Yahoo Finance geladen oder können aus beliebigen HTML Seiten extrahiert werden.</li>
      <li>Durch das offene Dateiformat stehen alle Daten als XML zur Verfügung oder können als CSV exportiert werden.</li>
      <li>Unterstützung für Rebalancing anhand von frei definierbaren Asset Allocations.</li>
      <li>Mit Hilfe der historischen Wechselkurse der Europäischen Zentralbank (ECB) können Konten und Aktien in Fremdwährung geführt werden.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>Office</category>
    <category>Finance</category>
    <category>Java</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>finance</keyword>
    <keyword>portfolio</keyword>
    <keyword>investment</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <releases>
		<release version="0.65.0" date="2023-08-14">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>New: Suggestions of providers for historical prices for freshly imported securities from PDF or CSV files</li>
					<li>New: Newly recognized securities can be assigned to existing securities during PDF import</li>
					<li>New: Pie chart of earnings (dividends, interest) by taxonomy</li>
					<li>New: Added support for PDF bank documents from Sberbank Europe and BISON</li>
					<li>New: Introducing a new "crosshair" tool available in the price charts</li>
					<li>Improvement: Date format is now automatically pre-filled during CSV import based on the current language setting</li>
					<li>Improvement: CSV import now supports scientific notation for numbers</li>
					<li>PDF Importer Enhancement: Expanded support for Raiffeisenbank, eBase, FlatEx, Quirion, Geno Broker, LGT Bank, and PostFinance</li>
					<li>Fix: Tooltip for calculating price gains is now limited to 50 rows</li>
					<li>Fix: Filter options are now properly applied when opening the list of all transactions</li>
				</ul>
				<ul xml:lang="de">
					<li>Neu: Vorschläge zur Kursversorgung von frisch importierte Wertpapiere aus PDF- oder CSV-Dateien</li>
					<li>Neu: Neu erkannte Wertpapiere können beim PDF Import bestehenden Wertpapieren zugeordnet werden</li>
					<li>Neu: Kuchendiagramm der Erträge (Dividenden, Zinsen) nach Klassifikation</li>
					<li>Neu: Unterstützung für PDF-Bankdokumente von Sberbank Europe und BISON hinzugefügt</li>
					<li>Neu: Neues Werkzeug "Fadenkreuz" in den Kursdiagrammen verfügbar</li>
					<li>Verbesserung: Das Datumsformat wird beim CSV-Import automatisch gemäß der aktuellen Spracheinstellung vorausgefüllt</li>
					<li>Verbesserung: Der CSV-Import unterstützt nun auch wissenschaftliche Schreibweisen für Zahlen</li>
					<li>Verbesserung der PDF Importer: Raiffeisenbank, eBase, FlatEx, Quirion, Geno Broker, LGT Bank und PostFinance</li>
					<li>Fix: Tooltip zur Berechnung der Kursgewinne auf 50 Zeilen limitiert</li>
					<li>Fix: Filteroptionen werden nun ordnungsgemäß beim Öffnen der Liste aller Buchungen angewendet</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
    <release version="0.64.5" date="2023-07-23">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix: Fixed an issue where new securities were mistakenly added to the watchlist of another file.</li>
          <li>Fix: New securities are now created in the reporting currency when the provider does not provide currency information.</li>
          <li>Improved PDF importer for GENO, sBroker, FlatEx, FFB, DKB, Deutsche Bank.</li>
        </ul>
        <ul xml:lang="de">
          <li>Fix: Behebt ein Problem, bei dem neue Wertpapiere fälschlicherweise der Watchlist einer anderen Datei hinzugefügt wurden</li>
          <li>Fix: Neue Wertpapiere werden in der Berichtswährung erstellt, wenn der Provider keine Währungsinformationen zur Verfügung stellt</li>
          <li>Verbesserung der PDF Importer: GENO, sBroker, FlatEx, FFB, DKB, Deutsche Bank</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.64.4" date="2023-07-15">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix: Fixes Cannot invoke “name.abuchen.portfolio.model.SecurityProperty.getType()” because “p” is null</li>
        </ul>
        <ul xml:lang="de">
          <li>Fix: Behebt Cannot invoke “name.abuchen.portfolio.model.SecurityProperty.getType()” because “p” is null</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.64.3" date="2023-07-15">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix: Fixes a problem with migration of filter configuration if identical filter exist</li>
        </ul>
        <ul xml:lang="de">
          <li>Fix: Behebt ein Problem mit der Migration von Filter-Konfigurationen wenn identische Filter existieren</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.64.2" date="2023-07-14">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>New: Filter configurations are no longer stored in the settings but in the file itself. This makes it easier to synchronize them between computers and to edit them better</li>
          <li>New: MACD indicator in the price chart (Moving Average Convergence/Divergence)</li>
          <li>New: the Measurement Tool is now active for all - it allows to easily measure distances and changes in the charts</li>
          <li>Improvement of PDF importers: LGT Bank, sBroker, Bondora, FlatEx, Trade Republic, Vanguard</li>
          <li>Improvement: More possibilities to create new instruments (securities, crypto currencies, etc): via keyboard shortcut Ctrl-N, via the (+) symbol next to "Securities" in the page navigation</li>
          <li>Improvement: Tables from the tooltips remember the column widths</li>
          <li>Improvement: tooltip for yields per year now contains all years</li>
          <li>Improvement: columns with the ticker symbol in the classifications</li>
          <li>Fix: Update of latest price via Yahoo Finance is fixed</li>
        </ul>
        <ul xml:lang="de">
          <li>Neu: Filter-Konfigurationen werden jetzt nicht mehr in den Einstellungen sondern in der Datei selber gespeichert. Damit können die einfacher zwischen Rechnern synchronisiert werden und besser editiert werden</li>
          <li>Neu: MACD Indikator im Kursdiagramm (Moving Average Convergence/Divergence) (zu Deutsch: Indikator für das Zusammen-/Auseinanderlaufen des gleitenden Durchschnitts)</li>
          <li>Neu: das Measurement Tool ist jetzt für alle aktive - damit kann man einfach in den Diagrammen Abstände und Änderungen messen</li>
          <li>Verbesserung der PDF Importer: LGT Bank, sBroker, Bondora, FlatEx, Trade Republic, Vanguard</li>
          <li>Verbesserung: Weitere Möglichkeiten neue Wertpapiere anzulegen: per Tastaturkürzel Ctrl-N, über das (+) Symbol neben "Wertpapiere" in der Seitennavigation</li>
          <li>Verbesserung: Tabellen aus den Tooltips merken sich die Spaltenbreiten</li>
          <li>Verbesserung: Tooltip zu den Erträgen pro Jahr enthält jetzt alle Jahre</li>
          <li>Verbesserung: Spalten mit dem Ticker Symbol bei den Klassifizierungen</li>
          <li>Fix: Aktualisierung des aktuellen Kurses über Yahoo Finance wieder möglich</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.64.1" date="2023-06-25" />
    <release version="0.64.0" date="2023-06-17" />
    <release version="0.63.1" date="2023-06-04" />
    <release version="0.63.0" date="2023-06-04" />
    <release version="0.62.1" date="2023-05-07" />
    <release version="0.62.0" date="2023-04-01" />
    <release version="0.61.4" date="2023-03-14" />
    <release version="0.61.3" date="2023-02-24" />
    <release version="0.61.1" date="2023-02-21" />
    <release version="0.61.0" date="2023-02-05" />
    <release version="0.60.2" date="2023-01-11" />
    <release version="0.60.1" date="2022-12-29" />
    <release version="0.60.0" date="2022-12-18" />
    <release version="0.59.5" date="2022-12-04" />
    <release version="0.59.4" date="2022-11-20" />
    <release version="0.59.3" date="2022-11-06" />
    <release version="0.59.2" date="2022-10-09" />
    <release version="0.59.1" date="2022-08-22" />
    <release version="0.59.0" date="2022-07-17" />
    <release version="0.58.5" date="2022-06-19" />
    <release version="0.58.4" date="2022-06-04" />
    <release version="0.58.3" date="2022-05-31" />
    <release version="0.58.2" date="2022-05-30" />
    <release version="0.58.1" date="2022-05-30" />
    <release version="0.58.0" date="2022-05-29" />
    <release version="0.57.2" date="2022-04-18" />
    <release version="0.57.1" date="2022-04-04" />
    <release version="0.57.0" date="2022-04-03" />
    <release version="0.56.6" date="2022-03-05" />
    <release version="0.56.5" date="2022-02-06" />
    <release version="0.56.4" date="2022-01-23" />
    <release version="0.56.3" date="2022-01-09" />
    <release version="0.56.2" date="2021-12-02" />
    <release version="0.56.1" date="2021-11-22" />
    <release version="0.56.0" date="2021-11-07" />
    <release version="0.55.0" date="2021-09-20" />
    <release version="0.54.3" date="2021-08-15" />
    <release version="0.54.2" date="2021-07-29" />
    <release version="0.54.1" date="2021-07-26" />
    <release version="0.54.0" date="2021-07-18" />
    <release version="0.53.3" date="2021-06-27" />
    <release version="0.53.2" date="2021-06-20" />
    <release version="0.53.1" date="2021-06-16" />
    <release version="0.53.0" date="2021-06-13" />
    <release version="0.52.0" date="2021-04-18" />
    <release version="0.51.3" date="2021-03-28" />
    <release version="0.51.2" date="2021-03-14" />
    <release version="0.51.1" date="2021-03-02" />
    <release version="0.51.0" date="2021-03-01" />
    <release version="0.50.4" date="2021-02-07" />
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
  <launchable type="desktop-id">info.portfolio_performance.PortfolioPerformance.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/info.portfolio_performance.PortfolioPerformance/HEAD/images/screenshot1@2x.png</image>
      <caption>Dashboard showing performance trend of portfolio for different years</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/info.portfolio_performance.PortfolioPerformance/HEAD/images/screenshot2@2x.png</image>
      <caption>Pie chart of the holdings in the portfolio</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/info.portfolio_performance.PortfolioPerformance/HEAD/images/screenshot3@2x.png</image>
      <caption>Historical performance chart of an index</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/info.portfolio_performance.PortfolioPerformance/HEAD/images/screenshot4@2x.png</image>
      <caption>Comparison of portfolio performance against an index</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <developer_name>Andreas Buchen</developer_name>

  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/portfolio-performance/portfolio/issues</url>

  <!--FIXME: where to donate to the application-->
  <!-- <url type="donation">http://www.homepage.com/donation.html</url> -->

  <url type="help">https://forum.portfolio-performance.info/</url>
  <url type="faq">https://forum.portfolio-performance.info/c/faq</url>
  <url type="translate">https://poeditor.com/join/project?hash=4lYKLpEWOY</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/portfolio-performance/portfolio/blob/HEAD/CONTRIBUTING.md</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/portfolio-performance/portfolio</url>

  <update_contact>info@portfolio-performance.info</update_contact>
</component>
